The best time to join crypto is now. It really is. I want to see if you trust me enough for me to
share some feedback with you. I want to see that I trust you enough to not be afraid to say something
real to you. Nothing is ever as bad as it seems and nothing is ever as good as it seems like
keeping a level ahead. When you're running a company, the worst thing you can do is spread
yourself too thin, right? But then you have to be flexible. Then you have to jump on trends.
How do you decide which one is the real winner? Crypto is feast and famine, right? Sometimes
you eat really well and sometimes it feels really, really bad. It feels like you're crazy
for working in this industry. We start predicting what is going to happen. But what we bet on is
something that's timeless. Something that I know is going to be true even 10 years, 20 years from now.
I'll call meme coins as, you know, it's like attention, tokenized attention.
I would like you to name maybe three to five projects that you are betting very big on.
A few favorite projects in crypto. So I think number one, this is something that I've loved
for a long time. It's a really new project, but I love it.
Hi, Jack. How's it going?
You're the co-founder of Magic Eden. I want to know about how you grew up, what you were doing
before Magic Eden. I'll tell you a little bit about my life. And actually, my life is before Magic
Eden was actually kind of deeply tied with crypto and actually a lot of my co-founders as well. We've
all been friends for a long time. But basically, the story was, yeah, I grew up in China. I moved
to Australia when I was very young in primary school, and that's where I grew up. And in high
school, that's actually where I met our technical co-founder, our CTO, Sid. We went to high school
together. We went to math tutoring together on the weekend. That's where we first met. So we've known
each other since we were like 15. What happened was during college, Sid and I, we would hang out
and we're really into startups. So we would try different ideas. And one thing that Sid did was,
this was around 2014, when we first graduated from college. That was when like the first Bitcoin bull
market was happening. He said, you know what? I want to do this crypto thing because not a lot of
people are doing it. So he actually started a Bitcoin company in 2014 and like raised some money and
moved to the US. Because he was one of my best friends, I was very inspired. He said, hey, you
know what? You should come to the US and maybe you should join my company, right? So I went to Boston
to check out what he was doing. And then I said, hey, dude, I don't know that much about business.
I don't know that much about building software, but I just definitely know your business is not
going to work. That's basically what I told him. And then I said, dude, I can't jump into this.
I'm sorry. I have to go back to Australia and find a real job, a quote unquote real job.
But what happened was, in some ways, it was a good move because his business went down in flames a few
months later. From that moment on, this was 2014. That's when I started learning about Bitcoin and
started learning about crypto. And I thought it was really fascinating. And it was so OG. At that time,
crypto was not on X. It was not on Twitter, right? It was on Bitcoin.org, these really old school
forums. And I went back to Australia. And long story short, I joined this big consulting company
in Australia. Then they sent me to the US, sent me to San Francisco in the Bay Area.
And I changed jobs to get into tech, do product management. But what ultimately happened was,
almost like at every point in my life or in my career at that point where I had the opportunity
to change jobs, I thought about joining crypto because I thought about this experience I had with Sid,
where he was asking me to join crypto. So when I came first to the US, I said, oh, maybe I should
join a crypto company. And then I moved to Google and I was like switching between different teams
at Google. And I thought, man, maybe I should join a crypto company. But each time I felt like,
yeah, I also had some fear. I was like, oh, this feels super weird. Like, is this going to survive?
Like, what's the state of technology? So I didn't jump in. I just mostly dabbled in playing
with tokens and playing with coins and buying coins and stuff. But ultimately, it was in 2021,
where there was this huge NFT boom. Right. And I thought, actually, this feels like a consumer
moment for crypto. Like, it's no longer talking about hardcore trading. It's no longer talking
about really like complicated financial terms for the everyday person to understand. Right. Like,
staking, consensus algorithms, this kind of stuff. It's no longer really talking about like deep
infrastructure. Like, which chain is faster? NFTs was more about partying, culture, games,
shit talking on the internet. To me, that's what consumer is. It's what like the everyday person
finds interesting. Right. It's like funny. It's entertaining. It's something that you can relate
to. 2021. That's when I thought, hey, maybe there's something here. We should do something.
Then I caught Sid back and he was like, not doing crypto anymore. And I said, hey, man,
like, let's do round two. You know, you started a crypto company like, you know, in the 2014 bull
cycle. But this is this time that could be something real. So that's how we basically got the company
started. You said you worked at Google and I assume you are making pretty comfortable salary.
Take me back to the moment when you're like, F this. I'm starting my own thing. What were you
thinking? I think there were a couple of things because of the story of seeing one of my really
close friends starting a company in crypto in 2014. I already had this thought of like, hey,
I want to do something. Why didn't I want to jump into crypto before this? I always felt like I did
not have an edge. I felt that most of crypto history, it's been either about hyper financialization.
So hardcore trading or it's been about deep infrastructure. So then hardcore trading is like
people who worked on Wall Street, built exchanges, built trading shops, those people could have
outside success, right? And then hardcore infra is like, oh, if you have a PhD in computer science,
you worked on distributed systems, then you could build the next chain. And that those people have
outside success. But most of my career has been in consumer internet, like UI, UX, building delightful
experiences, how to build things with millions of users. I always felt like, well, I have nothing to
contribute to this space because that's not what this space valued. But what happened was in 2021,
like effectively, there was like rise of Solana, fast chains. There was rise of like consumer use
case, like NFTs, like culture, games, art. That's when I thought, hey, this is a unique moment where I
could actually contribute something. And then at that time, also, I felt that I guess it was in COVID,
right? Like during COVID. I don't know, like a lot of people started thinking about what they're
really into. And I had a similar feeling. My similar feeling was, I got like a lot of good logos on my
CV, but I didn't feel like I was doing something for myself. And ultimately, when I was at Google,
I felt like, man, I have nothing left to prove. I worked on a bunch of these products, a lot of the
products scale to like billions of dollars in revenue. I thought, I don't need to collect any
more logo, like, you know, CV credentials. I should do something for myself. So all of this
basically came full circle together. And you talked about Solana and Magic Eden started
as Solana-based NFT marketplace. Solana obviously dropped to single digit after the last crypto crash.
And now it's all time high. Are people bullish enough?
The story of Solana really resonates with us at Magic Eden. So I think the key thing is about
thinking long term, having a lot of conviction in the thing that you're building, and then telling
yourself like nothing is ever as bad as it seems and nothing is ever as good as it seems,
like keeping a level head. So I'll tell you the two stories. I think one is Solana going from $250
to $8 and then having its renaissance. But then us knowing Raj and Anatoly pretty well and seeing them
having so much conviction, having so much calm through that when the whole world did not believe
them. I think that's actually a very inspirational story. And that energy is something that we try to
embody within Magic Eden as well. And then in Magic Eden, we had like the same mirror basically,
because when Solana was $250 and they dropped at $8, we saw our revenue drop 99%. It almost meant that
nothing we did at Magic Eden mattered because the sold price was so low. And at that time,
I think one of the best things that we did for Magic Eden is to expand cross-chain. So then we like
went to Polygon, ETH, Bitcoin, and became one of the only crypto projects that have like a lot of
traction in different ecosystems. And at that time, during the bear market, everyone was saying this is
crazy. And now, you know, Magic Eden in 2024, we've had our best year ever, like our most profitable
year. But it's because of those high convictions that bets that we made when it was really, really down.
So I think all of that is saying, we love this energy, like high conviction energy from Sol. And
that we also try to embody that at Magic Eden. It's also helped us.
What was it like when Sol was at $8? Like what was the energy? You said it's high energy,
but how do you stay positive when it's $8?
This is something we say at Magic Eden from really early, like month one at Magic Eden.
We tell the whole team, nothing is ever as bad as it seems and nothing is ever as good as it seems.
In fact, I just told my team two weeks ago, we had like a company outside and I said exactly the
same thing because it's bull market. Things are going to get crazy. And what that really means is
when things are really good, like bull market, you feel like you're the master of the universe.
It's actually not like that. And we should like pair ourselves down and be more humble and be more
level-headed. But in the bear market, as you say, when Sol is at $8, we should also tell ourselves,
nothing is ever as bad as it seems. If you're building something fundamental, focus on the
inputs, then the outputs will prove itself. That's the thing that we've been telling our team from
month one, like very early on. And I think it's really important. How can you have conviction?
The only way to have conviction is to say, hey, when we did really, really well, we should also
recognize there was a healthy dose of luck, right? We worked really hard, but someone, the universe
was looking out for us as well. So we should be humble. And then when things are really bad,
we should also tell ourselves like, well, fundamentally, the team did not drop 99%. The product that we built
did not drop 99%, right? Our talent did not drop 99%. So we should still have belief within ourselves about the
strategy and the mission that we are on. So yeah, that's something that we've been telling ourselves
for a very long time.
I feel like that's what true leaders do. Like they encourage your team, but I don't think anybody is
born a leader. And as you mentioned, you raised 130 mil in nine months. So I want to ask you, so how
and where did you learn how to fundraise? Because Jen Sun Huang from NVIDIA, he said he still can't figure
out how to write a business plan. How did you do it?
I don't think we wrote like a business plan as well. We had a vision, maybe a couple of things,
right? I would say there is no silver bullets. There's only lead bullets. What I mean by that is
like, there's no one single thing. You just have to do a lot of small things. You know, how did we
raise money? I think the core of it is, well, we were executing really well from all these like small
things leading up to it. And that gave us the credibility to raise. It wasn't that it was an
amazing like sales pitch or an amazing PowerPoint deck or anything, but it was more a testament to
a lot of the execution that we did leading up to that point. And it wasn't just me, it was the
whole team. I cannot take full credit by any means. I can only contribute a small part. It was more that
our whole team contributed to the success and the success then led us to be able to raise that much.
I think the second thing is that having like a long-term thesis and long-term mission is really
important. And this is something that is very much related to the thing I said earlier, like
think long-term, nothing is ever as good as it seems, nothing is ever as bad as it seems. This
is something that we had very early. But crypto as an industry is very short-term. People just build
products for a year, a few months, print the token, get rich, and then leave. And what we have
always wanted to do at Magic Eden is to outline some long-term thesis. So the same story for us was,
we believe in a multi-chain world. We believe in a multi-chain world, therefore we are going to be
a multi-chain marketplace. And therefore we are going to build a team that can do this. And we
have thesis about why multi-chain is the way, because we want to onboard casual users and those casual users
really value convenience, one single place to see everything. And I think that spirit of having a
thesis really early on, having the thesis of multi-chain, but then sticking with it. And of
course, the execution that led up to it, that's what gave us credibility to do that stuff. But
as I said, it was no one single silver bullet, but just like a lot of lead bullets along the way.
Would you say meme coin is NFT 2.0?
I've had someone ask me that a couple of times recently. So I think my short answer is no,
but I'll give it in a few different layers. Number one, how we see NFTs is NFTs is just the technology.
And creators use that technology to build use cases on top of it. And then there's use cases
like PFPs, music, gaming tickets, yada, yada, yada. That's how we see NFTs. And the relationship
with meme coins is this. I think in every technology, there is a speculative use case. So just like NFTs
can be used for speculation for PFPs, like fungible tokens like ERC-20s, SPLs, they can also be used for
speculation. And meme coins, I think is effectively like speculation based on, you know, fungible tokens
and PFPs is some element of speculation based on NFT technology. But how I see the space evolving is
if you take fungible tokens, eventually multiple use cases exist. There is like speculation use case,
then there's utility use case, then there's other things. And you could see that before,
right? In 2017, when ICO is really hot, it was basically a speculation, but eventually some
tokens with utility like Solana, they rode to the top and those things became massive.
I think for NFTs, it's going to be the same. There is this like speculative aspects, like PFPs and so
on and so forth. But then we will also see other categories rise as well, which uses technology for
like utility use cases. So that's basically how I see the relationship with the token. So I don't think
meme coins is NFT 2.0 because that's like using a use case to explain the technology. But I think
definitely like there is both things can have some speculative aspect and those things will continue
to live. And, you know, that's a part of parts of just being crypto.
And do you think NFT will still be a big thing this cycle?
To me, the story of NFTs for this cycle is even if NFTs is still pretty moderate, even if it's much
lower than the last bull market, I still have a lot of belief that magic eat it, we're going to do
really well because of the strategies that we put in and because of the product that we built.
So I think that's the first thing.
The second thing is that we are like, have this core part of our product, which is doing like
profile photos, Ordinals, BTC, this kind of thing. But we are also seeing some really interesting
new categories as well.
So one of the categories that we've always been really hot for NFTs is gaming.
And this cycle with now, I think we're seeing some new games that is really leading up to the dream
that we had before. So there is Off The Grid, which is built on Avalanche, and we're going to do a
partnership with them. That one is basically it has like 5 million users, number one on the Epic
game store. People don't really know it's crypto, but that thing is going to print like millions of
NFTs. And of course, we would like to be the commerce layer for those. I think it just needs a few hits for
like that to bring it to life. So that's the second thing. And I think the third thing for us is
Magic Eden, our business, like after we adopt the ME token, for example, it's really going to the next
chapter. And what we want to be and what we're going to look like is, I think, like an on-chain
version of finance, where we can trade multiple different types of categories of assets.
But it's all decentralized, and it's all on-chain. So for that, today, like fungible token trading is
already 20% of our business. So it's already pretty big, and it's only going to grow bigger. So I think
for this cycle, it doesn't really matter to us whether NFTs come back this cycle or not. But I
think for us, we're always going to have like a platform and a business that's going to be able to
ride multiple different waves. Earlier, you were talking about BRC20. So you're known for being very
fast and flexible. So when you saw BRC20, you're like, hey, let's add this to the platform. Am I
correct? Yes, we added BRC20. But I think for Bitcoin, our fungible tokens, probably what we're more
known for is ruins, which is like the effective, like a newer version of BRC20. But yeah.
Right, right. That too. Okay, so my question for you, as a company, like when you're running a company,
it's the worst thing you can do is spread yourself too thin, right? But then you have to be flexible,
then you have to jump on trends. Like how do you decide which one is the real winner?
There's a very, very true part of your question, which is it's very dangerous to spread yourself too
thin. We think about it as mission versus opportunity. In generally, we try to put our
mind as 70% mission, 30% opportunity. And of course, it's not like a hard and fast rule. I'm not
like measuring it with like a tape rule. It's like, am I 70%? It's not. It's just a conveyor spirit.
The spirit of it means this. Crypto is very fast moving and everything is changing all at the same
time. We have to have a long term vision and a long term mission for what we are building. For example,
the first chapter of Magic Eden is to become the number one cross chain NFT marketplace, which we
did. And we have like 60-70% market share in terms of revenue within NFTs. The next chapter of Magic
Eden in terms of long term mission is to become on-chain Binance, trade multiple assets across
multiple categories, all chains, all assets. That's our long term mission. And we put the vast
majority of our effort, let's say like 70% towards that mission, right? And we have to build a product,
we have a vision for the product looks like. But 30% opportunity is like, well, but we should
always keep an open mind. So the 30% of keeping an open mind is, as you say, like how Bitcoin
happened, how ruins happened, how ordinals happened, because we saw things in the ecosystem.
And we're like, oh, we're very, very interested in doing that. And then we should actually take a
side quest to do this really well. So that is what mission opportunity means. Then to your question
of not spreading yourself thin, the other thing that we tell ourselves is whatever we build,
we try to build best in class. Like we would like to be the best product for that category for what
we are trying to do. We don't want to build like half-assed things, right? Basically, to put that
simply. So therefore, if we actually decide to take a bet, and it's a side quest, ultimately,
the way we think about it is, yeah, we have to resource that accordingly, we have to put a team
that's really passionate about it. They're happy to dig at it, grind at it for a long time to
ultimately to build something that's really good. Like if someone wants to work for you,
what's the first question? I usually ask them a question about motivation. So I tell them like,
hey, crypto is feast and famine, right? Like sometimes you eat really well. And sometimes
it feels really, really bad. It feels like you're crazy for working in this industry. So
why do you want to work in crypto? And what gives you the motivation to keep going when times are
really bad? And usually we want to hire people, not because people are joining Magic Eden because
the times are good, but we want to hire people because you will still be here when times are
really bad as well. And you'll have conviction to stick through. So that's my number one question.
I see. You said Magic Eden is really profitable. So if I read correctly online, you are the most
profitable NFT marketplace, but not the one with the most market share. Is that correct?
I wouldn't say whether marketplace with the most volume, right? But I also think that
volume is like a vanity metric. It's very easy to be gamed. And that's why we chose like revenue and
users as our metrics. And I would say Magic Eden is the number one platform by users and number one
platform by revenue. User count, you mean? User count, yeah. Can you break it down for me? So
obviously there are other platforms that started earlier, right? Yeah. So how do we become this?
Yeah. So a couple of things like, yes, I think Magic Eden is number one by users over the past year,
right? And then of course, then we cannot look at like all lifetime because we've only been around
for three years. Some other platforms have been around for much longer. But over the past year,
Magic Eden is number one by users and number one by revenue. Just to close the loop on a previous point,
I think that only when users are willing to pay for the product that you built, to me, that is the true
sign of product market fit, right? Then it's like, oh, we are actually building something that's
valuable. So we stopped looking at volume. We only look at users and revenue. And to your question of how,
how do we get there? I think there's two parts to our strategy. One is betting on cross-chain,
which is like horizontal. And then the other one is building a wallet on top of our marketplace,
which is going vertical, right? It's like vertical integration. I think going cross-chain is,
this is the thesis we had from day one, which is crypto is too hard to predict what's going to happen.
I think this is very related to the previous questions that you have to be flexible. It's too
hard to predict. It's hard to predict like why volume is really high today, why this meta is
really hot today, why meme coins is hot. It's impossible. It's impossible to build a long-term
company like that. Therefore, our strategy is this, which is we don't predict. We start predicting like
what is going to happen. But what we bet on is something that's timeless, something that I know is
going to be true even 10 years, 20 years from now. And what is timeless is that most users,
like except for very advanced users, most users, they want something that's simple and they want
something that's convenient and they want something that's trusted. That's what they want. So if I have
a marketplace that gives them the maximum range, it's like Amazon. So whatever you want to look for
today, whatever is hot today, you can come and find out magic either. Then we are happy to bet that
strategy and we'll have to bet on that strategy for 10 years. So this is why we did cross-chain. We
did Sol, Bitcoin, ETH, and we're like number one in a lot of ecosystems. So that is about betting on
cross-chain. And it's a very expensive strategy because you have to have multiple teams working
on multiple pieces of technology. The second thing is to the point of like, why do we even have the
most users, right? We built our own wallet. So one of the things I realized in the last bull market,
Magic Eden, we did a lot of partnerships with like big brands. So I did like partnerships with
Shaquille O'Neal, partnerships with like Tomorrowland, you know, but no users came to Magic Eden. Why?
Because they hear about Magic Eden, they hear about Shaquille O'Neal, and then they have to go to
Coinbase. Then they go download a wallet, Phantom or Metamask. And by the time it comes to Magic Eden,
I get 0.001% of the users. We cannot grow like that, right? And of course, when we are a cross-chain
platform, I cannot force the user to download Phantom for Solana, download Metamask for Ethereum,
download Exodus for Bitcoin. That's not going to make it. We cannot grow. So that's why we built our
own wallet to say, now you have one-stop shop. You want to use any chain? You want to use base,
AveChain, Bitcoin, just use the Magic Eden wallet, and then you can connect to all the chains at the
same time. You can easily bridge your funds between different chains. And that allows us to grow as
well. So that is how we were able to basically acquire more users by basically making these
seamless and doing this like one-stop shop strategy. I love that because sometimes when I talk to really
OG founders, they're just like, oh, we have this product. You just need to swap and cross and do this
and this trick and that trick. And then you get there. And so it's easy, right? And I'm like,
no, it's not.
It's not.
And then, yeah, that's why we pursue this all chains, all assets strategy. And that's why we
pursue this product that's about simplicity, right? And this is all, even back to your first
question, question one, like, why do we start Magic Eden? What's my story? My story is in consumer
internet building for hundreds of millions of users. And to your point, it's almost like,
why are we surprised as an industry that we don't have hundreds of millions of users on chain?
Yeah, because you cannot force users to download five different wallets, use five different dApps
that basically do the same thing, right? And then you have to go find the bridge and like,
do this, do that. It's just, it's too complicated, right? It's too complicated.
And a lot of people have to fake that they understand to fit in. I feel like that's what
people go through. They have to be like, oh yeah, of course I know how to use that. Of course I know
how to swap. And people are like, they actually don't know. I think that's the struggle a lot of people
go through. No, definitely. When we decided to launch Magic Eden Wallet, so Magic Eden Wallet,
most of our focus is on mobile app. Our mobile app launched three months ago. We've got 150,000
downloads, which I think is pretty good for three months, three months of work. But to answer your
question, why did we decide to do Magic Eden Wallet? We wanted to basically acquire users, but I
remember asking inside the company, I said, how many people have tried our Bitcoin marketplace?
And of course our Bitcoin marketplace is one of our most successful products. Like we have 99%,
you know, share of the market. It's doing really great. And only like 5% of the company or 10% of
the company have used the marketplace. And I said, yeah, and I said, guys, that's, this is actually the
problem of our industry. We at Magic Eden, we are like a NFT, very deep NFT company. We are all very
crypto native. We are like advanced users of crypto. And we even have not even tried Bitcoin. Then I said,
man, if we cannot even get 100% of Magic Eden to use our Bitcoin marketplace, how can we expect to build
on more hundreds of millions of users? It's not going to work. So this is why we have to bet deep and have
conviction. Did you pivot after you asked that question?
We were already decided to build our own wallet, but we were thinking how much priority and how much
resourcing to put in it. Because it's so heavy, like building a wallet is like building a separate
company, right? There's entire companies dedicated to building wallets. But once I gave that very simple
example, everyone understood. It's like, okay, we have the strategy, we want to onboard a lot of users.
It's not going to work unless we make the wallet work. We have to make the wallet work. And then that's
when we decided to bet really deep and build something really good.
I mean, it's so simple, but I love it. Yeah, it's just so simple. You ask questions and you get the answer.
Yeah. We have a lot of newcomers because of Bitcoin all time high and like all the, you know,
ball run news all over the place. So for people that don't understand BRC20, Ordinals or Runes,
how would you explain to them?
Runes, BRC20s, you can basically think about it as like fungible tokens on Bitcoin.
Or today, Runes is basically meme coins on Bitcoin. And Ordinals is effectively like NFTs on Bitcoin.
And how I would explain it to them is probably in terms of the opportunity, right? I don't know if
you've seen this graph on Twitter. I think that graph is like really interesting to show to newcomers.
But it's basically like the size of meme coins and DeFi that's on Bitcoin versus meme coins and DeFi on Ethereum
versus meme coins and DeFi on Sol. And of course, like meme coins and DeFi on Ethereum and Sol is like very big,
but it's very small on Bitcoin. And to me, like that's how I would explain to people like the opportunity is huge.
Now it's possible to have meme coins and DeFi on Bitcoin through Runes, right? Through Ordinals,
through BRC20s. And if you get in here, then it's like a lot of upside, right? There's a lot of innovation,
a lot of wide space and of course, a lot of growth potential as well. So basically, that's how I would explain to them.
Bitcoin is being called digital gold, but Solana is not. Ethereum is not. So I feel okay betting my Sol on meme coins,
but I would, you know, be very nervous if I bet my Bitcoin on meme coin. What do you say to that?
Basically, what I would say is like, there are different types of users with different types of motivations.
It's the same, like, I don't know how much of my portfolio I will put into meme coins,
but I know there's people like even in our company who put like 80, 90% of their portfolio into meme coins.
Oh man.
I think it's, yeah, exactly. So to me, it's just, there's always going to be different investors,
users in the ecosystem with different motivations. Some people want to hold for a really long time
and they have a narrative that they really resonate with. Some people want to like go for like fast flips and that's okay.
We have a different type of product, but a different thing. The thing that I would definitely share with you,
and I think I basically share your sentiment, which is Bitcoin is like the mainstream crypto for this cycle.
It's like the thing that has global brand and we're in the fortune position to be like the largest dApp on Bitcoin.
And what we want to do is not just do ruins, not just do ordinals, but eventually as new innovations happen on Bitcoin,
we want to do those things as well. Like if lending, if Bitcoin L2s, those things become live and possible.
Of course, we also would like to innovate in those areas so that as Bitcoin gets more mainstream adoption,
then we basically write the brand as the best place to buy Bitcoin, to trade Bitcoin,
to trade Bitcoin assets, to lend Bitcoin, like all of these kinds of things.
That's something that we're very interested in.
I guess your parents might ask you what you're busy doing every day and you're like,
oh, there's this thing called meme coin that's very popular in crypto right now.
And they're like, what's meme coin? How would you explain?
Yeah, I don't know if I would tell my parents about meme coin.
Basically, I'll call meme coins as, you know, it's like attention, right?
Tokenized attention. And the way I kind of explain crypto in general to a lot of people is
crypto has this financial technology aspect to it.
And one of crypto's superpowers is that you can create markets on things that did not have markets before.
Right. You can allow things to be traded on things and concepts that couldn't be traded before.
Like NFTs is a good example.
And now I think meme coins is the same.
Like the concept of attention, you cannot trade that.
That was not like something that could be assetified.
Right. But now with crypto and with this like very like long tail financial technology,
you can turn that thing into an asset and give it a price and allow it to be traded.
So I think meme coins is kind of like that.
What I would actually say that though is it's super volatile.
It's super risky.
I don't know if I would recommend them to go into it, but it appeals to certain people.
Like there are a bunch of like folks within our company who are really hard on it.
And we're also developing products for that in our mobile app and it's getting traction.
So yeah, horses for courses.
Some users find this really helpful.
Well, I'm happy to serve those users.
EMI Foundation's TGE is in December.
And what's the strategy behind it?
Magic Eden, we're like adopting the EMI token, right?
And like EMI Foundation is a separate company.
So like they should talk about their strategy.
But I can talk a little bit about our strategy for like adopting the EMI token.
For Magic Eden, after we adopt the EMI token,
effectively there is going to be three big pillars to our strategy.
And our vision is to make digital ownership universal,
which is basically the onboard hundreds of millions of users on chain, right?
Into our platform, but also experience the on chain economy.
Those three pillars are like product, the EMI token, and community.
Product, as I've mentioned before, is the next chapter is we want to become on chain binance,
trade fungible tokens, trade NFTs, all chains, all assets.
And I think that's really important because we as an industry,
we are actually moving towards more fragmentation and more complexity.
There's like more chains.
There's more dApps that basically do the same thing.
There's more wallets that basically do the same thing.
And as we've been talking about,
it's very hard for newcomers to really understand what's going on, right?
It's really, really hard for newcomers to understand what's going on.
And we believe that because we've learned so much about going cross-chain,
about going deep in each ecosystem and getting traction,
we are the right team to build this product of all chains or assets
that will look like an on-chain version of Binance.
I think what we learned from the NFT space is we already have product market fit.
We're able to grow.
We're able to have diversified platform,
but we're also able to build something very seamless.
That's the product aspect of it.
What we then want to use ME to do is basically catalyze us into the next stage of our growth.
So we want to show our users and show the community
what the next version of Magic Eden is going to look like.
That's why adopting ME is going to happen in our mobile app.
In a mobile app, you can then see like,
oh, there's token trading as well.
We allow like swap from Bitcoin to Sol,
some very, very unique things that will happen in the mobile app.
And this is all to show the community what the next stage of Magic Eden,
the product is going to be.
So that's number one.
I think that number two is,
I think adopting the token is a way to unify the community.
And what we want to do, especially with this bull market,
is then to rally the community behind our mission.
Our mission is make digital ownership universal.
And that means building really simple retail-oriented products,
abstracting away the complexity for everyone,
and allowing everyone to have this like convenient one-stop shop.
And of course, doing it with a team that's very long-term aligned.
So to me, if I can use the token to rally
and unify the community behind our mission,
I think this is going to be really powerful for us
to build evangelists and bring like more users onto the space
and bring more users into our ecosystem.
So that's basically our thinking behind adopting the ME token,
how we can best show off our next version of our product,
but also rally the community behind what we're doing.
Not financial advice,
but I would like you to name maybe three to five projects
or maybe just altcoin trends that you are betting very big on.
Except for, you know, of course, Magic Eden is one of them.
Yeah, so I don't, so not financial advice.
And I generally like, I'm not going to talk about tokens
because we are, yeah, our philosophy is more like long-term, long-term builders.
But yeah, a few favorite projects in crypto.
So I think number one, this is something that I've loved for a long time,
but it's Brave, the browser.
I also think it's honestly one of those products
that is bringing more people into crypto,
but most people don't even realize they're using a crypto product.
And they probably have one of the biggest crypto applications
in the space altogether.
The last numbers I saw was like 50 million monthly active users,
probably more by this stage.
So in general, I love that project, right?
About building for the long term, bringing more users on the space.
It's a really new project, but I love Moonshot.
It's like this main trading app.
It basically, again, it's this story of like simplicity.
You don't have to build something really degen,
really complicated, really for the pro user.
And actually, Moonshot has really shown that it's onboarding like millennial,
Gen Z, basically like a very young audience into crypto.
And a lot of those folks have never been,
don't even have a Coinbase account.
There is a really big market out there
and a market that's waiting to be onboarded into crypto,
but we just have to build the right product for them.
So those are the two that I think I love.
Something from that's very OG, like Brave,
and something that's very new.
But in general, I think it goes to the ethos
of like bringing more folks to the space,
not following the everyday trend of like crypto Twitter.
What's your advice for people
that want to start their own project
or maybe work at a crypto company?
What's the advice?
The best time to join crypto is now.
It really is.
I think about my story of like first coming in contact
with crypto in 2014, 10 years ago.
And we had these dreams of like building amazing crypto products.
But back then it was not possible.
But today it really is possible.
So I think it's the best time to join now.
And then the other thing I would say is move quick today,
but think long term over many years.
Believe in something that's authentic to you
and just build it over the long term.
I actually think that there's not enough people doing that.
And if you actually do that,
then you actually stand out.
That's the best way to stand out.
But then it's very hard for people to do it alone.
You found, I mean, your best friends,
you know, they are your co-founders.
How do you actually identify the good quality
in your potential co-founder?
Because you know, the number one reason why startups fail
is the co-founders start to hate each other
and they disband.
That's actually the number one reason I think is very important.
I think the, to your question of how do you find the best quality,
the best quality is really trust.
And what trust means is,
are you able to say something really real to your co-founders
about something that you really don't like
about what they're doing?
And then they will take it the right way and say,
hey, thank you for sharing that feedback with me.
Let's work on how we can improve this together.
I think that's the most important thing.
But actually one of the best things
that I think contributed to where Magic Eden is today
and why, you know, we are successful today is
we did so much work to say,
hey, we should just be real.
We should actually tell each other what we're feeling.
And what we're feeling,
some of them could be very uncomfortable.
They could be some very uncomfortable truths.
But we are not saying it to criticize each other
or with negative intention.
It's not that.
It's something that needs to be said,
but it needs to be said
so that we can make our relationship stronger
and make the company better.
Being able to say that
without feeling like you'll be taken the wrong way
or feeling afraid to not say it,
I think that's a signal for trust.
And if you have that trust,
then the co-founders will really come together
and build something great together.
Sounds like romantic relationships.
It's a safe one.
Yeah.
Well, yeah.
Yeah, I think that's true
because, you know,
you should be doing that
with your husband and wife.
It's the same thing, right?
Like, you know,
you should be talking about some real shit
and working through it.
If you don't talk about it,
you can't hide away from it
because you need to talk about it eventually anyway.
So I think there is some truth to that.
But I do feel like, though,
it is not something you can know
before you have a conflict.
It's like when you're picking your co-founders,
everyone's like so nice.
Yeah, of course, I'm a people person.
I accept criticism.
And when shit really hit the fan,
everyone's like,
I don't know.
It's very difficult.
Yeah.
Well, before you start a business together,
I think you probably know a little bit.
You know, you know a little bit
about what that person is
and do you have that trust or not, right?
You probably know a little bit.
And in general, I think
this will feel really like
motherhood apple pie,
like really like fluffy.
But, you know,
I think you would know it in your heart.
If your heart says,
hey, I'm not fully comfortable,
eventually those small things
will turn into very big things.
What we actually do inside Magic Eden is
it's like every problem is an opportunity.
There's a really great saying.
It's called the obstacle is the way.
And what it means is that
when you face an obstacle,
that is the problem that comes with success.
And you have to just
see it as an opportunity to get through it.
We should be glad conflict happens
because when the conflict happens,
that's an opportunity for all of us
to get to know each other.
Then you have a real example to say,
hey, I want to see if you trust me enough
for me to share some feedback with you.
I want to see that I trust you enough
to not be afraid to say something real to you,
right?
And for us to work through it.
And you cannot shy away from that.
Like, we have to lean into it, right?
The obstacle is the way.
I really like that.
That's going to be in the highlight.
I love it.
Advice for newcomers,
like new retail users.
What I would actually say is that
especially over the last bear cycle,
so like let's say the last two years,
two and a half years,
crypto got a really bad name, right?
Crypto got a bad name.
Like people went to jail.
Some really famous founders went to jail.
Some really famous blobs happened.
Even as a builder,
as a founder in the space,
I felt it
because a lot of people would say,
man, like crypto is a scam.
Why are you working here?
And to the newcomers
that's joined the industry,
what I want to tell them is,
hey, high integrity and goodness
and people building something
for the long term live here.
And I hope that you,
and ultimately,
goodness resonates with good people.
And for those newcomers
who are in the space
who are searching for a brand
that's high trust,
who are building a product
that makes their lives easier,
who are going to be here
for the long term
and not like rug, right?
And whose incentives
are fully aligned with them.
Those companies
and those products exist.
And Magic Eden is one of them,
but there are many
that's like us as well.
So I hope that they can come here,
not just like see the innovation
of what this crypto
and what this technology is,
which is fun,
is exciting,
but they can still see that
like integrity and goodness
is here as well.
And they can find a company
and find a project
that they resonate with
and they can follow.
It's been great talking to you,
honestly.
And thank you for all the stories.
I love them.
Thank you.
Awesome.
Thank you for the opportunity.
Bye.